

CHESHI EMMANUEL

07038797502, 09018697877 emmychesh@yahoo.com, emmychesh17@gmail.com. No.43B Fudawa Bauchi Ring Road, Jos, Plateau

SKILLS

State.

- ♦ Quantitative And Qualitative Research
- **♦** Data Science/Analysis
- **♦** Python Programming
- **♦** Microsoft Office
- **♦** Microsoft Power BI
- **♦** Microsoft Excel
- **♦** IBM SPSS
- ◆ Atlas TI
- **♦** Data Collection
- Data Entry
- **♦** Machine Learning
- **♦** Model Deployment
- **♦** Teaching And Training
- ♦ Transcription

PERSONAL QUALITIES

- Data analysis
- **♦** Data collection
- **♦** Data Entry
- ◆ A good team player
- **♦** Computer literate
- **♦** Flexible
- ♦ A fast learner
- **Time management**
- Self-motivation and conflict resolution

SUMMARY

A Freelance Researcher, Data Analyst (Quantitative and Qualitative), Data Collection and Entry Expert, A Transcriber, Data Scientist, Python Programmer, Machine Learning Engineer a Remote Worker with over 5 years of experience in different research and analytical works (both Qualitative and Quantitative). My goal is to become associated with a company/organization where I can utilize my skills and gain further experience while enhancing the company's productivity and reputation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep.2023-Present

BLUEHOUSE TECHNOLOGIES Lead Data Scientist

As the Lead Data Scientist at Bluehouse Technologies, I play a multifaceted role in driving data-driven initiatives forward. I lead projects, develop strategies to achieve business goals, and optimize machine learning models for maximum effectiveness. Manage data quality and communicating insights to stakeholders. I stay abreast of industry trends, collaborate across teams, ensure ethical standards, and mentor junior data scientists to foster growth and excellence within the organization. I leverage data as a strategic asset, guiding our company towards innovation, efficiency, and sustainable growth.

Jul.2023 - Nov.2023

10ALYTICS ED-TECH HUB

Full Stack Data Science Facilitator

Responsible for instructing and guiding fellows in the end-to-end data science process. Using Python Programming Language, I emphasized meticulous data collection and preprocessing, provided comprehensive training on exploratory data analysis and predictive model development. Facilitated seamless model deployment and integration while mentoring fellows in performance monitoring and optimization. Actively fostered a data-driven culture and communicated technical concepts to non-technical stakeholders.

Sep.2022-Present

PICTDA (PLATEAU STATE INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY DEVELOPMENT AGENCY). Jos, Plateau State.

Data Science Instructor

Working as a Data Science tutor for Code Plateau Tech Hub, A unit of PICTDA saddled with the responsibility of teaching and training individuals who have interest in the tech field with programs such as Data Science, Blockchain Technology, Software Engineering, Digital Marketing. UI/UX etc.

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

- Proficient in computer applications, Windows environment, Microsoft word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Very conversant with quantitative and qualitative statistical tools SPSS, Atlas ti, Power BI etc. and can carry out various types of data analysis with the tools
- Data Collection Tools, Google Forms, Microsoft Forms. Kobo toolbox

LANGUAGES

- ◆ English
- ♦ Hausa
- ◆ Gbagyi

HOBBIES

◆ Reading, Listening to Music, Playing Football, Research and Analysis

Feb.2023-Feb.2023

CYPA AFRICA AND EQUITY INTERNATIONAL INITIATIVE. Jos, Plateau State.

Data Analyst

Worked as a data analyst for the Citizens Observers Hub and Data Center for the 2023 General elections hosted by CYPA (Center for Youth Participation) and EII (Equity International Initiative) collating, analyzing and visualizing real time results and updates of the 2023 General Elections and presenting a comprehensive report from the process.

Mar.2020 - May.2022 CAFOD UK | Jos Plateau State Nigeria

Researcher

Worked as a researcher, conducted qualitative research in Jos-North Local Government Plateau State Nigeria. The research was on peace building amongst the two major religious faiths in the location as a result of the incessant religious conflicts among the two dominants religions.

Mar.2020 - May.2022 CAFOD UK | Jos Plateau State Nigeria **Data Analyst**

Worked as a qualitative data analyst. Analyzed qualitative research findings from field data collected from case studies in line with particular research works in questions using qualitative analytical tools e. g Transcriptor and also Atlas ti

Jan.2017-Dec.2017

Precious Prince and Princess Montessori School | Benin City Edo State Nigeria

Academic Staff

Worked as an academic staff in this school. I taught the senior classes (Senior Secondary School Students 1-3) Chemistry, Geography and **Mathematics**

Apr.2015-Oct.2015

Quintessential Healthcare Center, Jos, Plateau State. | Jos Plateau State Nigeria **Social Worker**

Worked as an Intern and also a Social Worker. Had daily sessions with patients/clients who are addicted to different substances and drugs which have led to varieties of psychological and mental disorders, take them on daily sessions using treatment plans drafted out together with the patient to enable them reintegrate back into the society and also being fully functional.

CERTIFICATES OBTAINED

- ◆ Data Science with Python
- Introduction To Python Programming
- Data Analysis with Power BI
- Jobberman Soft-Skills
 Training Certificate
- National Youths Service Corps
- ◆ Teachers Registration Council of Nigeria
- ◆ SSCE (WAEC Certificate)
- Primary School Certificate

REFEREES

◆ Available on Request

Apr.2015-Oct.2015

Daisyland Orthopedic and Trauma Hospital, Jos, Plateau State. | Jos Plateau State Nigeria Occupational Therapist

Worked as an Intern and also an Occupational therapist. I assisted accident victims who have successfully undergone orthopedic surgeries with therapeutic exercises to enable them be able to carry out their day-to-day physical needs step by step until they fully recover from their injuries.

May.2013-Oct.2013

Open Doors Special Needs Education Center, Jos Plateau State.

Educator

Worked as an Educator, Special Educator for children with various disabilities both physical to cognitive disabilities ranging from Mild, Moderate, Severe to Profound disabilities. This is in a bid to enable these children learn the "normal" educational curriculum despite their disabilities.

EDUCATION

Sep.2018-Jul.2020 University of Jos | Jos Plateau State Nigeria

General And Applied Psychology

Postgraduate Diploma

Obtained a Post-Graduate Diploma Degree in General and Applied Psychology.

Sep.2011-Jul.2016 University of Jos | Jos Plateau State Nigeria

Rehabilitation Sciences

Bachelor of Science in Education

Obtained a Bachelor's Degree in Education (B.

Sc. Ed) Rehabilitation Sciences

May/June 2011/12 Divine Grace High School | Jos Plateau State

Nigeria

West African Senior School Certificate
Obtained My Senior School Certificate

Sep.2005-Jul.2008 Baptist Science Grammar School, Jos Plateau

State

Junior School Certificate

Obtained my Junior School Certificate after successfully passing my Junior certificate

examination

September 2005 University of Jos Primary School | Jos

Plateau State Nigeria

First School Leaving Certificate

Obtained My First School Leaving Certificate.